# Han Wei **NEO**

# Data Scientist

(+65) 8606 8770

@ nhanwei@gmail.com

Singapore

in linkedin.com/in/nhanwei/

github.com/nhanwei



# **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

Data Scientist with 5-6 years of experience in building Machine Learning models to solve hard problems using big data. In Singapore's largest bank, I built their first Deep Learning based Recommender System for product advertisements. Besides Data Science, I have a professional passion in joining the dots between multiple stakeholders especially product owners and data engineers.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST**

#### Metis, Singapore

• Led the Metis Data Science Bootcamp in Singapore as the Main Bootcamp Instructor and Senior Data Scientist.

- Past Cohorts:
  - San Francisco Spring 2019 (April 2019 June 2019)
  - Singapore (July 2019 September 2019)

#### **FOUNDER**

# **CodeAI**, Singapore

CodeAI is a professional Python and Data Science Coaching Institute.

• Founded CodeAI with the aim of improving coding literacy in Singapore by providing quality and accessible programming classes.

#### **DATA SCIENTIST**

# Jul 2018—Mar 2019

#### PALO IT, Singapore

- Deployed an asynchronous **R** model as an API using plumber, future, docker on MS Azure for a Reinsurance company in Australia.
- Built POCs on Object Detection, Natural Language Processing and Sentiment Analysis.

# **DATA SCIENTIST**

#### Oct 2016-Jul 2018

Mar 2019—Present

Jun 2019—Present

#### DBS Bank, Singapore

- Responsible for building Machine Learning models for DBS Bank's regional markets: Singapore, Hong Kong and China.
- Developed a **Deep Learning based Recommender System** for product advertisements on internet and mobile banking in Singapore using Keras, TensorFlow and Python.
- Developed the User-Based Collaborative Filtering Recommender System in China using R.
- Built models that attained at least 4X uplift for multiple cross-sell, up-sell and **acquisition** projects across numerous products using **R** and **Python**.
- Created a Machine Learning pipeline in R using H2O and R Shiny. Used by other co-workers.
- Mentored fresh hires in building Machine Learning models.

# **KEY SKILLS**

Python

Keras

TensorFlow

Machine Learning

Deep Learning

PySpark

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

Distributed Computing

(Hive/Hadoop)

**AWS** 

MS Azure

Docker

Apache Pig

Git

SAS

Tableau

#### **EDUCATION**

# National University of Singapore

Master of Computing, Computer Science 2019

# National University of Singapore

Bachelor of Science (Hons), Statistics 2015

- Second Upper
- Won 1st Prize in a R Programming competition open to all Singapore universities undergraduates.
- Co-wrote a R package on Hamiltonian Monte Carlo method for Final Year Project (See elhmc).

#### **DATA ANALYST**

June 2015—Sep 2016

# StarHub, Singapore

- Mined terabytes of raw, unstructured and structured telecommunication data using Apache Spark, Pig, R and Python.
- Developed geo-location algorithms to uncover subscribers' travelling and websurfing behaviors.

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology Summer Student Exchange Program 2014

# Other Activities

MOOCs 2014—Present

- Completed 34 MOOC courses (as of Aug 2019) that are related to Data Science.
- Completed 3 Coursera specialisations (Data Science, Deep Learning and TensorFlow in Practice).

# Kaggle

• Top 8% for Walmart Recruitment Competition (78<sup>th</sup>/1047)

# **Agile Fundamentals**

• ICAgile Certified Professional

#### MISCELLANEOUS INFORMATION

# Languages

• Native Proficiency in English and Mandarin (Oral and Written)